Lai Deming

LANGUAGES

English

Proficient

Details

Professional Full-Stack Engineer @ laideming935@gmail.com

Singapore, Singapore

Skills

Language

Java, C++, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, PHP

Front End

HTML, CSS, jQuery, Angular, ReactJS, Vue.js Bootstrap, Materialize, Selenium, Web Driver

Back End

JSP, Servlets, Maven, Gradle, JPA, Spring Boot
Webflux, JDBC, Hibernate, SQL, Oracle, gRPC
NoSQL(MongoDB, DynamoDB, Cassendra), C#
Spring Framework, RESTful APIs, Grails, Struts
C/C++, AWS & GCP, Terraform, JMeter, Mockito
TDD-Junit, Kubernetes, OpenShift, Multithreading
Kafka & RabbitMQ, Apache Spark, Docker,
Elastic Cache/Redis

Hobbies

Painting, Reading, Windsurfing

SUMMARY

I am an experienced full-stack web developer over 7 years of experience handling all aspects of the development process for high-scale web and mobile applications. My proficiency in diverse industries such as Blockchain, E-commerce, Healthcare, and

Education has allowed me to understand my client's business needs successfully. I have built and managed secure websites and possess comprehensive knowledge of web security. My expertise includes working with Linux command line tools, and I pride myself on writing clean, well-tested, and well-documented code. In addition to this, I

have successfully completed projects with tight deadlines in high-stress environments. As a result, I am resourceful, self-motivated, and proactive in ensuring project success. With a pragmatic approach, I handle the front-end to back-end tasks, including hosting, site design, and system administration. I do not shy anyway from responsibilities and never use phrases like "That's not my job." Throughout my career, I have collaborated with multi-functional teams and have been successful in delivering 40+ projects.

Education

Bachelor of Informatics engineering

2012-2016

Bandung Institute of Technology

Experience

Full Stack Engineer (Remote, Contract)

09/2021 - 04/2023

Mad Dog Car Club

Boston, USA

- Developed RESTful APIs using Java Spring Boot, NodeJS for a web application with over 1 million users per month.
- Developed frontend in Angular
- Used Kafka to Stream Data in backend side.
- Used Selenium and Web Driver to Scrape Data from Amazon
- Developed an engine in Scala with Spark to handle big data from AWS to increase their sales on Amazon
- Development, Management the product (multi microservices) using AWS Clouding Services(AWS Lambda, DynamoDB, SQS, EKS) in the development stage but later migrated into GCP.
- Monitoring the offshore work and providing technical help to the offshore team for their JIRA tickets.
- Performed the System Testing, Regression, Testing for Complete UI after fixing the issues which are reported by Testing Team.

Back end developer

10/2018 - 06/2021 New York, USA

AVANAN

- Responsible for backend API development in Python and NodeJS
- Responsible for deployment and management of NodeJS WebSocket Service in AWS Lambda
- Responsible for deployment and management of Python Backend Service in AWS EC2 instance - Ubuntu Server
- Partnering with teammates to discuss about solutions
- Responsible for identifying the gap, coordinate with external team for dependency resolution and closing the gap
- Responsible for analysis big database with mongoDB
- Partnering with Scrum master and Product manager in daily scrum call, resolving impediment related to mapping document, sprint planning and PI planning

Internships

06/2016 - 08/2018 Boston, USA

ASICS Digital

- Backend developer for Node.js project.
- Served as a friendly, hardworking, and punctual employee.
- Collaborated on high priority projects with tact and strong attention to detail.